The first metric of interest is Net Promoter Score or NPS.
第一个指标是净推荐值 (NPS)
NPS is a customer loyalty metric that is determined by asking users one question.
净推荐值是通过问用户一个问题以衡量顾客忠诚度的指标
On a scale of zero to ten, how likely are you to recommend this product or
分值从 0 到 10 你有多大可能将本产品或服务推荐给
service to a friend.
一位朋友
Customers who respond with a number between zero and
答案为 0-6 分的客户
six are called your detractors.
为贬低者
Customers who score seven or eight are your passives, and
7-8 分 为被动者
anyone ranking with a nine or ten is a promoter.
9-10 分 为推荐者
And to actually calculate your NPS you take their percent of promoters and
然后计算 NPS
then subtract out the percent of detractors.
推荐率减去贬低率
This actually means that NPS can fall between negative 100 and positive 100.
事实上这意味着 NPS 位于正负100之间
You could, for example, have everyone vote you between zero and six.
例如 你可以邀请每个人在 0-6 间进行投票
A good Net Promoter Score will vary by industry.
净推荐值随行业不同而不同
As you can tell from this chart, many industries have a wide range for
从这张图表中可以看到 许多行业的净推荐值区间
net promoter scores.
范围很广
And you can see their averages in these squares along the graph.
在曲线上的这些方框 可以看到它们的平均值
If you'd like to take a closer look at this chart,
如果想更仔细地观察这个图表
you can refer to it in the instructor notes.
可以参阅讲师注释
Click Through Rate is another metric that you'll find associated with website
点击率 (CTR) 是另一个与网站按钮
buttons, links, and e-mail campaigns.
链接、邮件推广相关的指标
With CTR, you're measuring whether or not a user took action.
通过 CTR 你可以测量用户是否会采取行动
CTRs are helpful for
CTR 有助于
determining how customers advance through steps of a purchase.
确定客户的购买程序进行到了哪一步
For example, one checkout flow could be on Udacity's website.
用优达学城网站的支付流程做个例子
We could collect data on how many users check out a homepage,
我们可以收集首页登陆量
go to a description page for a product, how many clicked to start a free trial,
产品详情浏览量和免费试用量方面的数据
and how many actually completed the payment information form to register for
以及多少用户填写了支付信息表
that free trial.
注册免费试用
Daily active users, or DAU, is another common metric, and
日活跃用户 (DAU) 是另一个常用指标
it can take on multiple meanings.
它具有多重意义
The trickiest part is defining what active means for your product.
最大的优点是阐明了“活跃”对产品来说意味着什么
It could be as simple as logging in, performing specific tasks, or
它可以很简单 比如登陆、执行具体任务或购买
making a purchase, depending on your business.
这取决于你的业务
You can track the number of users over time, and you'll likely see some
你可以一直跟踪用户量 日复一日
variation from day to day, maybe even a plateau, and then hopefully you'll see
你会发现一些变化 或者平稳 你可以预测
an uptick where you get a lot of adoptions from new users.
在获得众多新用户后 日活跃用户会小幅增加
By relating product launches, new features, press releases, and
将产品发布、新功能、新闻稿
even market research to this data, you can get a sense for
甚至市场调研和这些数据联系在一起 你就会知道
what might be driving your traffic.
网站流量的主要来源
These next three metrics are similar to daily active users.
这三个指标 (7-14-28 天活跃用户) 与日活跃用户指标类似
Except you're tracking active users,
除了跟踪活跃用户以外
in whichever way you define active over some defined period of time.
你还可以在特定时间段内 确认活跃量
So instead of having daily active users, you might have weekly active users,
除了日活跃用户 你可以追踪周活跃用户
or monthly active users.
或者月活跃用户
Here's a bar chart showing monthly active users for WhatsApp.
这个柱形图展示的是 WhatsApp 的月活跃用户
WhatsApp is a popular mobile messaging application.
WhatsApp 是一款非常受欢迎的移动短信应用程序
Now, you might be wondering why some of these bars are missing, and
你可能在思考为什么有些柱子看不见
it's just because the source of the data didn't have this information.
因为数据来源没有这个信息
It'd probably be better to show this as a line chart over time, but I
可能用线形图展示这个会更好
didn't want to give the impression that these points were actually in the data.
但是我不想说这些时间点已经包含在数据中了
To calculate any x day active users, you simply total the number of
计算任意天数的活跃用户 只需要统计
unique users who initiated sessions on your website or
起始日期至结束日期 通过网站或者移动应用程序
mobile application from a starting date all the way until the ending date.
登陆的单个用户的数量即可
You might also look at patterns over weekday or
你也可以关注工作日或者周末活动的图表
weekend activity to spot trends.
来查看趋势
For example, Twitter determined that if a user opened Twitter seven times in one
例如 Twitter 认为 如果某个用户一个月访问 Twitter 7次
month then the user was likely to return.
这个用户很可能再次访问
By attracting active users and possibly what features they use,
通过吸引活跃用户和他们可能使用的功能
you might determine what is driving users back to the product.
你就可以确定用户回来的主要原因是什么
And finally, another useful metric is retention.
最后 另一个有用的指标是用户留存率
It's the opposite of churn or attrition.
这与流失和自然减员正好相反
Retention describes the number or
用户留存率指
the percent of users you keep over a certain period of time.
一段时间内留存下来的用户数量或者比率
While not counting any new users you acquired during that same time interval.
不包含这段时间内吸纳的新用户量
Now, this example wouldn't really be that great, because I'm only keeping,
这个例子也许不是太好 因为
let's say, about 1% of my users after 12 weeks.
12 周以后我的用户留存率只有 1%
Even better, you can monitor cohorts of users
好处是 你可以根据用户开始使用产品和服务的时间
based on when they start using the product or service.
分别监测用户群
For example, you can create retention curves for two groups of users.
例如 你可以为两组用户制作用户留存曲线图
Let's say one group of users starts on January 1st,
比如一组用户在 1 月 1 日开始使用
while the other starts on January 8th.
而另一组用户在 1 月 8 日开始
To learn more about cohort analysis, check out this article
了解组群分析更多内容 请阅读 Nir Ariel博客上的这篇文章
on Nir Ariel's blog, which is linked in the instructor notes.
链接参见讲师注释
The article discusses how to measure retention and use cohort analysis,
这篇文章讲的是如何测量用户留存率和使用组群分析
while looking at user retention for Pinterest and Twitter.
同时还可以看到 Pinterest 和 Twitter 的用户留存率
Now, these are some of the common baseline metrics.
这些都是一些常用的基本指标
And whatever metric you choose, the metric needs to signal
无论选择哪个指标 这个指标必须能显示出
that users are using the product in an expected way,
用户在以预期的方式使用产品
and that the same users are likely to come back and use the product more.
以及用户可能变成回头客再次使用产品
This certainly isn't every metric that you might want, but
当然你并不需要所有的指标
these are some common ones that you'll use in most products.
这是一些在大多数产品中都会使用的常用指标
In the next video, we'll look at a framework for
在下一视频中 我们会讨论
how you can come up with other metrics.
如何提出其他的指标